[
  {
    "question": "Hansen's disease is more commonly known by which name?",
    "answer": "leprosy",
    "options": ["leprosy", "cancer", "stroke", "fatigue"],
    "id": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Botany is the study of what life form?",
    "answer": "plants",
    "options": ["environment", "insect", "plants", "animals"],
    "id": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the human body's largest organ?",
    "answer": "skin",
    "options": ["liver", "kidney", "heart", "skin"],
    "id": 3
  },
  {
    "question": " snails have teeth",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false", "maybe", "not-sure"],
    "id": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "What part of the human body is the Mandible?",
    "answer": "lower jaw bone",
    "options": [
      " beneath tooth gum",
      "upper jaw bone",
      "above the tongue",
      "lower jaw bone"
    ],
    "id": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "How many bones does an adult human have?",
    "answer": 206,
    "options": [302, 180, 206, 300],
    "id": 6
  },
  {
    "question": " jellyfish have hearts",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false", "maybe", "not-sure"],
    "id": 7
  },
  {
    "question": "Which French microbiologist discovered the process of pasteurisation?",
    "answer": "Louis Pasteur",
    "options": [
      "louis viton",
      "robert hooke",
      "felix dujardin",
      "Louis Pasteur"
    ],
    "id": 8
  },
  {
    "question": "What year was the first animal cloned?",
    "answer": 1996,
    "options": [2012, 2019, 1996, 1990],
    "id": 9
  },
  {
    "question": "Who discovered penicillin?",
    "answer": "Alexander Fleming",
    "options": [
      "Alexander Fleming",
      "ben carson",
      "theodor schwan",
      "luther mathus"
    ],
    "id": 10
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the Human Genome project completed?",
    "answer": 2003,
    "options": [2000, 2003, 2004, 2002],
    "id": 11
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species are estimated to live on Earth?",
    "answer": "8.7million",
    "options": ["1billion", "10thousand", "4.6million", "8.7million"],
    "id": 12
  },
  {
    "question": "A DNA molecule is described as being what shape?",
    "answer": "Double helix",
    "options": ["helix", "double helix", "spiral", "tetrahedal"],
    "id": 13
  },
  {
    "question": "Heterochromia results in which change in physical appearance?",
    "answer": "Different coloured eyes",
    "options": [
      "Different coloured eyes",
      "Different shin colour",
      "Different hair colour",
      "Different length of legs"
    ],
    "id": 14
  },
  {
    "question": "Crohn's disease is part of which disease group?",
    "answer": "Inflammatory bowel disease",
    "options": [
      "Inflamatory gum disease",
      "Inflamatory foot disease",
      "Inflammatory bowel disease",
      "Inflamatory jaw disease"
    ],
    "id": 15
  },
  {
    "question": "How many neck vertebrae do giraffes have, compared to a human's seven?",
    "answer": "seven",
    "options": ["seven", "eight", "nine", "ten"],
    "id": 16
  },
  {
    "question": "Which food substance helps move waste through the body?",
    "answer": "Fibre",
    "options": ["Fibre", "Athries", "Vein", "Spine"],
    "id": 17
  },
  {
    "question": "The term 'renal' refers to which organs?",
    "answer": "kidneys",
    "options": ["stomach", "lungs", "livers", "kidneys"],
    "id": 18
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the biggest part of the human brain?",
    "answer": "cerebrum",
    "options": ["thalamus", "medulla", "cerebrum", "cranial"],
    "id": 19
  },
  {
    "question": "cell walls be found in",
    "answer": "plant cells",
    "options": ["plant cells", "animal cells", "both", "none of the above"],
    "id": 20
  },
  {
    "question": "which is an animal",
    "answer": "salamander",
    "options": ["mango", "shrob", "salamander", "fern"],
    "id": 21
  }
]
